Geon-woo, wait for me.
건우 씨, 기다려주세요.
NOVEMBER 4, 2008 LIM NA-RI
2008년 11월 4일 임나리
-Cheers!
-건배!
Hey, Na-ri. What was his name again?
안녕, 나리. 그 사람 이름은 또 뭐였지?
Geon-woo. Kim Geon-woo.
건우. 김건우.
Let me see his pic.
그의 사진을 보자.
Let me see if he's really worth all this heartbreak you're going through.
그 사람이 정말 가치가 있는지 한번 볼까? 당신이 겪고 있는 이 모든 가슴 아픈 일들.
-What a load of crap. -Hey, you're gonna be shocked.
-정말 쓰레기같아. -야, 너 진짜 충격받을 것 같아.
Huh?
뭐?
-He's actually really cute. -Right?
- 실제로는 정말 귀엽습니다. -오른쪽?
Come on, he's just average. Nothing special.
어서요, 그 사람은 그냥 평균이에요. 특별한 것은 없습니다.
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
Next to him, you'd look pretty rough.
그 옆에 있으면 당신은 꽤 거칠어 보일 것입니다.
Is this him?
이 사람인가요?
The otaku loser?
오타쿠 패자?
Is it obvious?
분명합니까?
Goddamn it! It's obviously written all over him.
젠장! 분명히 그의 몸 전체에 쓰여 있습니다.
He totally lives up to his looks.
그는 그의 외모에 완전히 부응합니다.
Give it to me.
나에게 주세요.
Here it is.
여기 있습니다.
He says this is an app that grants wishes.
소원을 들어주는 앱이라고 하네요.
Fucking hell.
빌어먹을.
This isn't some fucking genie lamp.
이건 빌어먹을 지니 램프가 아니야.
He still believes it at his age.
그는 그 나이에도 여전히 그것을 믿습니다.
Grants wishes, my ass.
소원을 들어준다, 젠장.
Saying Geon-woo likes Se-ah and all that crap…
건우는 세아를 좋아한다며 그리고 그 모든 쓰레기들…
This app that grants wishes…
소원을 들어주는 앱...
Is it called Girigo?
기리고라고 하나요?
What the heck? You know about it?
도대체 뭐야? 당신은 그것에 대해 알고 있나요?
Hey.
여기요.
Hey, that Girigo thing
안녕, 그 기리고(Girigo) 물건
is real.
진짜야.
Hey. For fuck's sake.
여기요. 젠장.
Are you drunk?
취했나요?
Come on, you know.
어서, 알잖아요.
In exchange for a wish,
소원을 대가로
you have to give up your life.
당신의 인생을 포기해야합니다.
Cut the crap.
쓰레기를 자르십시오.
Just remember that.
그거만 기억하세요.
Hey, you believed me just now, didn't you?
야, 방금 내 말 믿었지?
Man, you're still a kid.
이봐, 넌 아직 어린애야.
Look at this innocent 18-year-old.
이 순진한 18세 소년을 보세요.
Hey, don't freak out. It's fine, okay?
이봐, 놀라지 마세요. 괜찮아, 알았지?
Hey, these guys came up with that thing to mess with some kid.
야 이 사람들이 그런 걸 생각해냈어 어떤 애랑 장난하려고요.
That's not true.
그것은 사실이 아닙니다.
Oh, don't deny it.
아, 부정하지 마세요.
You made it to mess with some loser.
당신은 패자를 엉망으로 만들었습니다.
I said it's not true.
나는 그것이 사실이 아니라고 말했다.
You normally give off Kwon Si-won vibes, but when you freak out,
평소에는 권시원 느낌을 풍기는데, 하지만 겁이 나면
I see a bit of Do Hye-ryung in you.
당신에게서 도혜령의 모습이 살짝 보이네요.
-You agree, right? -Fucking stop!
-동의하시죠? -젠장 그만해!
What?
무엇?
They really died back then.
그땐 정말 죽었거든요.
Just stop talking about it.
그것에 대해 이야기하지 마세요.
Na-ri, are you leaving?
나리야, 갈 거야?
You totally ruined the vibe.
분위기를 완전히 망쳤어요.
What did I do?
내가 무엇을 했나요?
What's wrong? I'm having fun.
무슨 일이야? 나는 재미있다.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
I'm gonna give it a go.
한번 해볼께요.
Since you said I remind you of a loser who fell for this,
당신이 내가 패배자를 생각나게 한다고 말한 이후로 누가 이 일에 빠졌어?
I kinda feel like falling for this too and making a wish.
나도 이거에 빠질 것 같아 그리고 소원을 빌어요.
GIRIGO THE APP THAT GRANTS WISHES!
지리고 소원을 들어주는 앱!
By the way, does this thing kill people for you too?
그건 그렇고, 이런 일이 있니? 너 때문에 사람도 죽여?
I'm offering my life. It should at least do that for me.
나는 내 생명을 바치고 있습니다. 적어도 나에게는 그렇게 해야 합니다.
Don't do it.
하지 마세요.
GIRIGO MAKE A WISH
지리고 소원을 빌어보세요
There are two people I want dead, okay?
내가 죽고 싶은 사람이 두 명 있어요, 그렇죠?
Cut the crap.
쓰레기를 자르십시오.
First is Choi Hyeong-wook.
먼저 최형욱이다.
You're a given.
당신은 당연한 존재입니다.
And then there is someone who's really pissing me off right now.
그리고 누군가가 있습니다 지금 누가 나를 정말 화나게 하고 있나요.
It's Dong-jae--
동재입니다--
Man, I feel like crap.
아, 기분이 쓰레기 같아.
God, my head is killing me.
맙소사, 내 머리가 죽고 있어요.
Hey!
여기요!
What the hell?
대체 뭐야?
What a freaking way to start the day.
하루를 시작하는 정말 끔찍한 방법입니다.
Hyeong-wook, put the knife down. Okay?
형욱아, 칼 내려놔. 좋아요?
What's wrong? Hyeong-wook. Put it down.
무슨 일이야? 형욱. 내려 놔.
Hyeong-wook, no!
형욱, 안돼!
Stop, Hyeong-wook.
그만해, 형욱.
Stop!
멈추다!
No!
아니요!
Get back in!
다시 들어가세요!
There are two people I want dead, okay?
죽고 싶은 사람이 두 명 있어요, 그렇죠?
First is Choi Hyeong-wook.
첫번째는 최형욱입니다.
You're a given.
당신은 당연한 존재입니다.
No.
아니요.
GIRIGO YOUR WISH HAS BEEN GRANTED
지리고 당신의 소원이 이루어졌습니다
IF WISHES COULD KILL
소원이 사람을 죽일 수 있다면
DONG-JAE
동재
The person you are trying to reach is unavailable.
연락하려는 사람 사용할 수 없습니다.
-The person you are trying-- -Damn it.
-당신이 시도하는 사람-- -젠장.
BE HAPPY OVER THERE, DONG-JAE
거기서 행복하세요 동재님
There is someone who's really pissing me off right now.
누군가가 있어요 지금 누가 나를 정말 화나게 하고 있나요.
It's Dong-jae--
동재입니다--
-Hey, did you guys hear? -What?
-야, 들었어? -무엇?
Hyeong-wook died because of Na-ri.
형욱은 나리 때문에 죽었다.
-That's so creepy. -No way.
- 정말 소름끼치네요. -안 돼요.
But why Hyeong-wook? He was so nice.
그런데 형욱은 왜? 그는 정말 친절했어요.
Shouldn't it be Lim Na-ri instead?
대신 임나리여야 하지 않을까요?
I know, right?
나도 알아, 그렇지?
Does that mean Se-ah's in danger?
그렇다면 세아가 위험하다는 뜻인가요?
Lim Na-ri was hitting on Geon-woo.
임나리가 건우를 때리고 있었다.
She's just like her mom. Her mom cheated on her dad.
그녀는 엄마와 똑같습니다. 그녀의 엄마는 아빠를 속였습니다.
No, her dad cheated, according to Se-ah.
아니요, 세아에 따르면 아버지가 바람을 피웠어요.
Hell if I know. Maybe her family's just a total mess.
내가 알면 지옥. 어쩌면 그녀의 가족은 완전히 엉망이 될 수도 있습니다.
You fucking bitches!
이 빌어먹을 년들아!
HEE-JIN
희진
Did the timer come up?
타이머가 나왔나요?
The timer?
타이머?
Did your training really get canceled?
훈련이 정말 취소됐나요?
Did your wish
소원대로 됐어
come true?
실현되다?
Cancel! Training! Cancel the training!
취소하세요! 훈련! 교육을 취소하세요!
-Cancel the training. -Please grant Geon-woo's wish.
-교육을 취소합니다. -건우의 소원을 들어주세요.
-When did your training get canceled? -11:26.
-훈련이 언제 취소됐나요? -11:26.
That's when you got the message?
그때 메시지를 받았나요?
-Yeah. -Maybe it's hacked.
-응. -해킹되었을 수도 있습니다.
Look. I'm telling you, this isn't a hack.
바라보다. 내가 말하는데, 이건 해킹이 아니다.
Can a hack kill someone?
해킹으로 사람을 죽일 수 있나요?
Hey, can an app kill someone, then?
그렇다면 앱이 사람을 죽일 수 있나요?
A lame app that grants your wishes?
소원을 들어주는 형편없는 앱?
It makes you kill yourself when the timer hits zero?
그것은 당신을 자살하게 만든다. 타이머가 0에 도달하면?
Do you seriously think that's real?
진지하게 그게 진짜라고 생각하시나요?
Whatever it is, it's no ordinary app.
그것이 무엇이든, 그것은 평범한 앱이 아닙니다.
It won't delete, even after a reset.
재설정 후에도 삭제되지 않습니다.
This won't stop either.
이것도 멈추지 않을 것이다.
Can't we just break the phone?
그냥 전화 끊으면 안 돼요?
We can't. Breaking the phone…
우리는 할 수 없습니다. 전화를 끊는 중…
Guys.
얘들아.
At times like this, we need to clear our heads
이럴 때, 머리를 비워야 해
and start with the simple stuff.
간단한 것부터 시작하세요.
Then let's get everything we need and meet at my place.
그럼 필요한 건 다 가져오자 그리고 내 집에서 만나요.
Na-ri.
나리.
You're coming too, right?
너도 올 거야, 그렇지?
Sure.
확신하는.
Yeah.
응.
Na-ri.
나리.
Why the fuck didn't you answer?
도대체 왜 대답 안 했어?
Na-ri, what's wrong with you?
나리야, 무슨 일 있어?
Get out.
나가세요.
I said get out.
나는 나가라고 말했다.
You knew this would happen, right?
이런 일이 일어날 줄 알았지?
I get Dong-jae was drunk and got pissed, but I was wondering what got into you.
동재가 술에 취해서 화를 냈나 봐요. 하지만 당신에게 무슨 일이 생겼는지 궁금해요.
I didn't see this coming either.
나도 이런 일이 일어날 줄은 몰랐다.
If I'd known Dong-jae would really die, I would've done anything to stop you.
동재가 진짜 죽을 줄 알았더라면, 나는 당신을 막기 위해 무엇이든 할 것입니다.
Or maybe you only cared about yourself.
아니면 자신에게만 관심이 있었을 수도 있습니다.
Na-ri.
나리.
You didn't actually believe in the app when you made that wish.
당신은 실제로 앱을 믿지 않았습니다 네가 그 소원을 빌었을 때.
Cut the crap! Just tell me what you know about Girigo!
쓰레기를 잘라! Girigo에 대해 알고 있는 것을 알려주세요!
A girl named Kwon Si-won created it to bully another girl, Do Hye-ryung.
권시원이라는 여자가 만들었지 또 다른 여자 도혜령을 괴롭히기 위해.
Do Hye-ryung died because of that app. That's all I know.
도혜령은 그 앱 때문에 죽었다. 그게 내가 아는 전부입니다.
Because of this?
이 때문에?
What is this?
이게 뭔가요?
That wasn't in the app I saw.
제가 본 앱에는 그런 내용이 없었습니다.
Then why did Do Hye-ryung die?
그렇다면 도혜령은 왜 죽은 걸까?
Suicide.
자살.
There were a lot of rumors that it wasn't suicide,
소문이 많이 나더라구요 자살이 아니었어
but they were all made up.
그러나 그것들은 모두 만들어졌습니다.
If they were all made up, why are people dying?
모두 구성했다면, 사람들은 왜 죽어가고 있나요?
I don't know either.
나도 모른다.
All I can tell you is,
내가 말할 수 있는 건,
if you really want to know about Girigo,
기리고에 대해 정말 알고 싶다면
go after Kwon Si-won, not Do Hye-ryung.
도혜령 말고 권시원을 쫓으세요.
Kwon Si-won was both the creator of Girigo and the shaman's daughter.
권시원은 기리고의 창작자이기도 하다. 그리고 무당의 딸.
Kwon Si-won?
권시원?
Kang Ha-joon!
강하준!
Wait for me.
기다려주세요.
Do you believe Se-ah?
세아를 믿으세요?
That Hyeong-wook died because of a curse on the app?
형욱이 죽었다고 앱의 저주 때문에?
I don't believe in superstition.
나는 미신을 믿지 않습니다.
Then what?
그러면 어쩌죠?
What do you think Girigo really is?
Girigo가 실제로 무엇이라고 생각합니까?
The most reasonable explanation is that Girigo is a smishing app.
가장 합리적인 설명 기리고(Girigo)는 스미싱 앱이라는 것입니다.
Hacking, like you said.
네 말대로 해킹이네.
Then why didn't you say that earlier in front of Se-ah?
그럼 왜 아까 그 말을 안 했어? 세아 앞에서?
Do you still like Se-ah?
아직도 세아를 좋아하시나요?
Do you still like Geon-woo?
아직도 건우를 좋아하시나요?
What about the timer?
타이머는 어떻습니까?
We can stop and delete the timer now, right?
중지하고 삭제할 수 있습니다. 지금 타이머 맞죠?
Yeah.
응.
Should I delete it?
삭제해야 하나요?
Yeah, leave no trace of it.
응, 흔적도 남기지 마.
Geon-woo, what's wrong?
건우 씨, 무슨 일이에요?
I don't know.
모르겠습니다.
I think I've got something in my eye.
내 눈에 뭔가 들어간 것 같아요.
Geon-woo, stop doing that. Just go rinse--
건우야, 그만 좀 해라. 가서 헹구세요--
There…
거기…
Geon-woo.
건우.
Don't do that.
그러지 마세요.
Na-ri, do you know where you are?
나리야, 너 지금 어디 있는지 알아?
Do you recognize me?
당신은 나를 알아보나요?
You are Se-ah's aunt.
당신은 세아의 이모입니다.
But how did I get here?
그런데 내가 어떻게 여기까지 왔지?
Don't you remember riding in the ambulance with your friends?
구급차에 탔던 기억 안 나? 친구들이랑?
Any headaches?
두통이 있나요?
I'm fine.
잘 지내요.
Yeah, it's not serious. You'll feel better after some rest.
응, 심각하진 않아. 좀 쉬고 나면 기분이 좋아질 거예요.
Geon-woo's folks are here. If they see you, it's gonna be a mess.
건우네 식구들이 왔어요. 그들이 당신을 본다면, 그것은 엉망이 될 것입니다.
Do you need anything?
필요한 것이 있나요?
Let me know. I can bring it from your home.
알려줘요. 집에서 가져올 수 있어요.
I'm okay.
난 괜찮아.
My aunt brought everything I needed earlier.
이모님이 가져오셨어요 이전에 필요한 모든 것.
But what about you?
하지만 당신은 어떻습니까?
Isn't your bag at my place?
당신 가방은 내 집에 없나요?
The passcode is my birthday, so just drop by and grab it.
비밀번호는 내 생일이고, 그러니 그냥 들러서 가져가세요.
Huh?
뭐?
Did the timer
타이머를 켰어
stop?
그만해?
Huh? Na-ri!
뭐? 나리!
Na-ri!
나리!
You still haven't gone home?
아직도 집에 안갔어?
No.
아니요.
You're here to see Geon-woo, aren't you?
건우를 만나러 오셨죠?
-Geon-woo's not in the ICU anymore. -Sorry?
- 건우는 이제 중환자실에 없어요. -죄송합니다?
He got better earlier, so we moved him to a regular room.
그는 더 일찍 좋아졌고, 그래서 우리는 그를 일반 방으로 옮겼습니다.
Oh my God, I'm so glad to hear that.
맙소사, 그 소식을 들으니 정말 기쁘네요.
When was this?
이게 언제였지?
It's been about an hour since he woke up.
그가 깨어난 지 약 한 시간이 지났습니다.
You can go visit him.
당신은 그를 방문할 수 있습니다.
Hey, Na-ri.
안녕, 나리.
If you see Se-ah,
세아를 보면
could you tell her I'm looking for her?
내가 그 사람을 찾고 있다고 전해줄 수 있나요?
She's not in her room, and I can't reach her.
그녀는 방에 없어요 그리고 나는 그녀에게 연락할 수 없습니다.
Okay, I'll do that.
알았어, 그렇게 할게요.
Se-ah.
세아.
Yoo Se-ah.
유세아.
"The timer does not stop"?
"타이머가 멈추지 않는다"?
Hyeong-wook died
형욱 사망
at 9:08.
9시 8분.
-When did your training get canceled? -11:26.
-훈련이 언제 취소됐나요? -11:26.
Geon-woo's wish was granted at 11:26.
11시 26분에 건우의 소원이 이루어졌습니다.
If I subtract 2 hours and 18 minutes from 24 hours,
2시간 18분을 빼면 24시간부터
that leaves 21 hours and 42 minutes.
21시간 42분 남았습니다.
That's when my timer stopped.
그때 내 타이머가 멈췄습니다.
After Geon-woo's wish was granted,
건우의 소원이 이루어진 후,
my timer stopped.
내 타이머가 멈췄어요.
Then why did Geon-woo's timer stop?
그럼 건우의 타이머는 왜 멈췄나요?
Geon-woo's wish was granted at 11:26.
11시 26분에 건우의 소원이 이루어졌습니다.
It's been about an hour since he woke up.
그가 깨어난 지 약 한 시간이 지났습니다.
Take away 9:32, when he regained consciousness.
9시 32분 그가 의식을 되찾았을 때
That's ten hours and six minutes.
10시간 6분입니다.
Subtracting ten hours and six minutes from Geon-woo's timer
10시간 6분 빼기 건우의 타이머에서
leaves 13 hours and 54 minutes.
13시간 54분 후에 출발합니다.
When Geon-woo woke up,
건우가 깨어났을 때
the timer stopped.
타이머가 멈췄습니다.
Yeah.
응.
How did things end up like this?
어쩌다가 일이 이렇게 됐지?
Se-ah must have made a wish.
세아에게 소원이 있었나봐요.
5. THE TIMER DOES NOT STOP
5. 타이머가 멈추지 않습니다
When a new timer starts,
새 타이머가 시작되면
the previous person's timer stops.
이전 사람의 타이머가 중지됩니다.
SE-AH
세아
The person you are trying to reach is unavailable.
연락하려는 사람 사용할 수 없습니다.
Please try again later.
나중에 다시 시도해 주세요.
HA-JOON
하준
No!
아니요!
No, Haetsal!
아니, 햇살!
When the door closes, you're done.
문이 닫히면 끝이에요.
At least you should get out so we can find a way, right?
최소한 나가야지 그럼 우리가 길을 찾을 수 있을 거에요, 그렇죠?
The person you are trying to reach is unavailable.
연락하려는 사람 사용할 수 없습니다.
Please try again later.
나중에 다시 시도해 주세요.
SE-AH, I FOUND A WAY THERE'S A WAY TO STOP THE TIMER
세아, 나 방법을 찾았어 타이머를 멈출 수 있는 방법이 있어요
AND I HAVE SOMETHING TO CONFESS TO YOU
그리고 당신에게 고백할 것이 있습니다
HYEONG-WOOK ACTUALLY…
형욱은 실제로…
YOO SE-AH
유세아
GEON-WOO, I FOUND A WAY TO STOP THE TIMER!
건우야, 타이머를 멈출 방법을 찾았어!
BUT KEEP THIS A SECRET FROM NA-RI
하지만 나리에게는 비밀로 해주세요
NOT ALL THREE OF US CAN MAKE IT OUT ALIVE
우리 셋 모두 살아남을 수는 없어
HOW DO YOU STOP IT?
어떻게 막나요?
I'LL TELL YOU IN PERSON, WAIT
직접 말씀드리겠습니다. 잠시만 기다려주세요
What the hell could it be?
도대체 무슨 일이 있는 걸까?
YOO SE-AH
유세아
Damn it!
젠장!
Should I dig into Ha-joon instead of Se-ah?
하준을 파헤쳐볼까 세아 대신?
They're both ignoring me, so they've gotta be together.
둘 다 나를 무시하고 있어요. 그래서 그들은 함께 있어야 해요.
Hey, what are you doing here?
이봐, 여기서 뭐 하는 거야?
Se-ah's aunt asked me to run an errand.
세아 이모가 나에게 심부름을 하라고 시켰다.
What about you?
당신은 어때요?
Let's talk inside.
내부에서 이야기합시다.
If you're gonna do that all day, I'm going home.
하루종일 그렇게 할거면 나는 집에 갈거야.
Give me my phone.
내 전화기를 줘.
I remembered something while watching your video.
뭔가 생각났어 당신의 비디오를 보는 동안.
I saw someone that day.
그날 누군가를 봤어요.
Up there.
저기요.
There was someone else there.
거기에는 다른 사람이 있었습니다.
What are you doing? It's scary.
뭐하세요? 무섭다.
She had a huge wound on her face,
얼굴에 큰 상처가 있었어
and the same uniform and name tag as us, but she didn't seem familiar.
그리고 우리와 같은 유니폼과 이름표, 하지만 그녀는 낯익은 것 같지 않았다.
A huge wound on her face?
얼굴에 큰 상처?
Yeah.
응.
Strange.
이상한.
If she were in our grade, we would've at least heard about it.
그 사람이 우리 학년이었다면, 우리는 적어도 그것에 대해 들었을 것입니다.
Wanna go to the school with me tonight?
오늘 밤 나랑 같이 학교 갈래?
Tonight?
오늘 밤?
I need to check something without the teachers finding out,
뭔가 확인해야 할 게 있어 선생님이 눈치채지 못하게
but I'm a little uncomfortable going by myself.
그런데 좀 불편해요 나 혼자 간다.
Could you help me?
저를 도와주실 수 있나요?
Sure.
확신하는.
But I can't go like this.
하지만 이대로는 갈 수 없어요.
Pick a time and place.
시간과 장소를 선택하세요.
I'll change and meet you.
갈아입고 만날게요
Okay. Thanks, Na-ri.
좋아요. 고마워요, 나리님.
The signal was last detected
신호가 마지막으로 감지되었습니다
at Gwangdong Apartments, Building 323.
광동아파트 323동
But I can't confirm the floor number.
그런데 층수는 확인할 수 없어요.
So is the phone off right now?
그럼 지금 전화는 꺼져 있는 건가요?
That would be my guess.
그건 내 추측일 것이다.
Nowadays, as long as the phone's on, it'll pick up either Wi-Fi or GPS.
요즘은 전화기만 켜져 있으면 Wi-Fi나 GPS를 선택합니다.
WHERE ARE YOU?
어디세요?
WHEN ARE WE MEETING UP?
우리 언제 만나요?
YOU'LL FIND OUT SOON, NO RUSH
곧 알게 될 것입니다. 서두르지 마세요
GEON-WOO I'M THE ONE WHO STOPPED YOUR TIMER :)
건우 타이머를 멈춘 사람은 바로 나예요 :)
ARE WE STILL KEEPING IT A SECRET FROM NA-RI?
우리는 아직도 그것을 비밀로 하고 있나요? 나리에서요?
YEAH, NOT ALL THREE OF US CAN MAKE IT OUT ALIVE
응, 우리 셋 다 그런 건 아니야 살아날 수 있을 거야
Geon-woo, wait for me.
건우 씨, 기다려주세요.
How did you know about the hole in the fence?
어떻게 알았어? 울타리에 난 구멍에 대해서요?
I made it.
내가 해냈어.
Huh? Why would you do that?
뭐? 왜 그렇게 하시겠습니까?
To get Se-ah on the national team.
세아를 국가대표로 뽑기 위해서.
Come on. Let's go.
어서 해봐요. 갑시다.
Hey, why are we going this way? The path's right there.
야, 우리 왜 이렇게 가는 거야? 길은 바로 거기에 있어요.
Be careful coming down.
조심해서 내려오세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
-What's that? -This?
- 그게 뭐죠? -이것?
Just a decoration.
그냥 장식입니다.
Hey, what are you doing?
이봐, 뭐하는 거야?
Getting a kid on the national team isn't easy.
아이를 국가대표로 키우다 쉽지 않습니다.
Let's go in.
들어가자.
Man, you scared me.
이봐, 너 때문에 겁이 났어.
When did you and Se-ah start going out?
세아랑 언제부터 사귀기 시작했어요?
We're not.
우리는 그렇지 않습니다.
Yeah, right.
응, 맞아.
Earlier, you punched in Se-ah's passcode and walked right in.
아까 세아 비밀번호 눌렀잖아 그리고 바로 들어갔다.
You're close enough to know each other's passcodes.
당신은 충분히 가깝습니다 서로의 비밀번호를 알기 위해
That was only because--
그 이유는--
That wish video you made while eating chicken
당신이 만든 그 소원 영상 치킨을 먹으면서
was at Se-ah's place.
세아 집에 있었어요.
It looked like Ha-joon caught on too.
하준도 낚인 것 같았다.
I'm just curious if that's what happens when you sneak around every night.
그냥 그런 일이 일어나는지 궁금해요 매일 밤 몰래 돌아다닐 때.
That's all.
그게 다야.
It's not like that. Well…
그렇지 않습니다. 글쎄… ​​
It hasn't been that long. I wasn't trying to hide it or anything.
그리 오래되지 않았습니다. 나는 그것을 숨기거나 아무것도하려고하지 않았습니다.
Sorry.
죄송합니다.
You like each other, so you're dating. Why apologize?
서로 좋아해서 사귀는 거에요. 왜 사과하나요?
I wasn't apologizing for us dating.
나는 우리가 데이트하는 것에 대해 사과하지 않았습니다.
I was apologizing for lying to you just now.
나는 사과하고 있었다 지금 거짓말을 해서요.
Unbelievable.
믿을 수 없는.
Hey, I lie to you all the time.
이봐요, 난 항상 당신에게 거짓말을 해요.
Why apologize for something like that?
왜 그런 일에 대해 사과합니까?
Like what, for example?
예를 들어 어떤가요?
Huh?
뭐?
Name one lie you told me.
당신이 나에게 한 거짓말을 한 가지 말해보세요.
Then what will you do for me?
그러면 당신은 나를 위해 무엇을 해줄 건가요?
Whatever it is,
그것이 무엇이든,
I'll tell you it's okay.
괜찮다고 말해줄게.
I lied about lying to you all the time.
나는 항상 당신에게 거짓말을 했다고 거짓말을 했습니다.
And the lie about that being a lie? Also a lie.
그리고 그게 거짓말이라는 거짓말이요? 또한 거짓말.
NURSE'S OFFICE
간호사실
We made it this far,
여기까지 왔어요
but how do we get in?
그런데 우리는 어떻게 들어가나요?
The nurse's office door is busted.
간호사실 문이 부서졌습니다.
So they really do keep these.
그래서 그들은 실제로 이것을 보관합니다.
So even years from now, they'd know I was bumming around here twice a week?
그러니까 지금부터 몇 년이 지나도 그들은 알 거예요 내가 일주일에 두 번씩 여기서 뒹굴고 있었나?
That's creepy.
정말 소름끼친다.
I hope there weren't kids like you.
너 같은 애들은 없었으면 좋겠어.
"Scraped knee, Choi Ju-a."
"무릎 긁힌 최주아."
"Suspected wrist sprain, Ju Da-hae."
"손목 염좌가 의심됩니다, 주다해님."
"Laceration with bleeding."
"출혈이 있는 열상."
"Kwon Si-won."
"권시원."
Did you find it?
찾았나요?
Na-ri.
나리.
She had a wound on her right cheek, right?
오른쪽 뺨에 상처가 있었죠?
You saw it too.
너도 봤잖아.
That female student.
그 여학생.
I didn't notice it the first time I watched your video.
나는 그것을 눈치채지 못했다 처음으로 당신의 영상을 봤죠.
I realized it the second time.
나는 그것을 두 번째로 깨달았다.
Why you kept moving the camera while filming empty space.
카메라를 계속 움직인 이유 빈 공간을 촬영하면서.
It seemed like you saw the same thing I did.
그것은 같았다 당신도 나와 같은 것을 보았지요.
Something the others couldn't see.
다른 사람들이 볼 수 없었던 것.
You said you were checking the video to find your phone.
영상을 확인하고 있다고 하더군요 휴대전화를 찾으려고요.
So you were just pretending you couldn't lie earlier?
그래서 넌 그런 척만 한 거야 좀 더 일찍 거짓말을 할 수는 없었나요?
Wow, Kim Geon-woo. This is new.
와, 김건우. 이것은 새로운 것입니다.
Do you have my phone too?
내 전화기도 갖고 있나요?
What if I told you I don't? Would you believe me?
내가 하지 않는다고 말하면 어떻게 되나요? 내 말을 믿으시겠습니까?
Na-ri.
나리.
I'm sure you had a valid reason for the lies you told me.
나는 당신이 타당한 이유가 있다고 확신합니다 당신이 나에게 했던 거짓말 때문이에요.
But from now on, let's be honest.
하지만 이제부터 솔직하게 이야기해보자.
Don't come closer!
가까이 오지 마세요!
You brought me to an empty school to scare me, didn't you?
넌 날 텅 빈 학교로 데려왔어 겁주려고 그랬지?
No, I just wanted to check if you'd actually seen that girl.
아니요, 그냥 확인하고 싶었어요 만약 당신이 그 여자를 실제로 본 적이 있다면.
In case I was mistaken.
내가 착각한 경우를 대비해.
Take one more step closer. I dare you.
한 걸음 더 가까이 다가가세요. 감히.
Brother-in-law.
처남.
We're the only ones who saw the girl in your video, Na-ri.
우리뿐이야 영상 속 여자 나리를 본 사람이요.
That puts us in the most danger.
그것은 우리를 가장 위험에 빠뜨립니다.
You don't know what it's like when she takes hold of you, do you?
넌 그게 어떤 것인지 모르잖아 그녀가 당신을 붙잡을 때, 당신은요?
We need to help each other. Okay?
우리는 서로 도와야 합니다. 좋아요?
I bet Se-ah can see her too now.
이제 세아도 그녀를 볼 수 있을 것 같아요.
What?
무엇?
A lot happened while you were out cold.
당신이 추운 동안 많은 일이 일어났습니다.
You want to know what kind of bitch Se-ah is?
당신은 알고 싶어 세아는 어떤 새끼야?
Do you see that?
저거 보이나요?
Some fucking friend she is.
그녀는 정말 빌어먹을 친구야.
Na-ri.
나리.
I went to the carrier this afternoon and suspended my service.
오늘 오후에 택배사에 갔어요 내 서비스를 중단했습니다.
I reported it stolen, signed out of all my accounts,
도난신고를 했는데요, 내 모든 계정에서 로그아웃되었습니다.
and wiped my number clean.
그리고 내 번호를 깨끗이 지웠어요.
You get what I'm saying?
내 말을 이해하셨나요?
No one can reach me on that phone right now.
누구도 나에게 다가갈 수 없어 지금 그 전화로요.
That phone's bricked, Na-ri. Okay?
그 전화기는 벽돌이 됐어요, 나리 씨. 좋아요?
You really did your homework.
당신은 정말로 숙제를 했습니다.
Hyeong-wook and I went through the same thing, the calls and texts.
형욱이랑 내가 겪은 일 똑같은 일, 전화와 문자.
Don't come any closer. Just listen!
더 이상 가까이 오지 마세요. 그냥 들어보세요!
You know everything, huh?
다 알고 계시죠?
Then you must know what my wish was.
그렇다면 내 소원이 무엇인지 아셔야 합니다.
"I wish for Choi Hyeong-wook to die."
"최형욱이 죽었으면 좋겠다."
Hey.
여기요.
Don't lie to me.
나에게 거짓말하지 마십시오.
You're right.
당신 말이 맞아요.
That's what I call a good lie.
나는 그것을 좋은 거짓말이라고 부릅니다.
But guess what?
하지만 그거 알아요?
I even have the wish video here.
여기에 소원 영상도 있어요.
Hey, are you okay?
이봐, 괜찮아?
Don't come closer!
가까이 오지 마세요!
I told you not to come any closer.
더 이상 가까이 오지 말라고 했잖아.
Na-ri!
나리!
Lim Na-ri!
임나리!
Why won't the door…
왜 문이 안 열리나요...
Hey.
여기요.
Na-ri!
나리!
Hey, Lim Na-ri!
안녕하세요, 임나리님!
GIRIGO DOWNLOAD
지리고 다운로드
BEGIN DOWNLOAD
다운로드 시작
Hey!
여기요!
Don't do that.
그러지 마세요.
-Are you okay? -Huh?
-괜찮으세요? -뭐?
Where's the girl you were with?
너랑 같이 있던 여자는 어디 있어?
The one you were yelling for!
당신이 소리 지르던 그 사람!
Who are you?
누구세요?
Stay still.
가만히 있어라.
Huh? Are you okay?
뭐? 괜찮으세요?
Done.
완료.
Huh?
뭐?
What's going on?
무슨 일이야?
Have you ever heard
들어본 적 있나요
that if you write down your saju and make a wish…
사주를 적는다면 소원을 빌고…
it'll come true?
그게 현실이 될까요?
Subtitle translation by: Sung In Jang
자막 번역: 장성인